# DIMITRA GIANTSIDI

https://dgiantsidi.github.io/ · dimitra.giantsidi@gmail.com Informatics Forum 1.05, University of Edinburgh 10 Crichton Street, EH8 9AB, Edinburgh, United Kingdom

I like to build robust and efficient distributed systems!

I am a final year PhD student at the University of Edinburgh, UK and as part of my research, I have worked on some interesting projects: a secure distributed transactional store (Trusted Execution Environments, RDMA and RocksDB), a shielded direct I/O network library for secure replication (Crash Fault Tolerance and BFT) and a fast shared log for serverless computing infrastuctures (byte addressable storage, gRPC/TCP). I am currently designing a trusted NIC architecture for large-scale distributed systems based on SmartNICs.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### ICSA, University of Edinburgh, UK

June 2023 - now

Research Assistant

- $\cdot$  Implementation of an RDMA-based smartNIC architecture for improved security guarantees.
- $\cdot$  Design and optimization of robust networking protocols for fault tolerance.

## Condidential Computing Group, Microsoft Research, Cambridge, UK

Sept 2021 - Dec 2021

 $Research\ Scientist\ Intern$ 

 $\cdot$  Design and implementation of a single-node KV store resilient to timing-attacks.

## Cloud RnD, Intracom Telecom, Athens, Greece

Jul 2017 - Jul 2018

Software & Systems Engineer

 $\cdot$  Performance and energy optimization of NFV services.

#### Unversity of Edinburgh, UK and TUM, Germany

Sept 2019 - present

Thesis advisor and Teaching Assistant

- · Operating Systems, Distributed Computing, Parallel Architectures, Object-oriented Programming.
- · Supervised five BSc/MSc students on their BSc Thesis on Distributed and Networking systems.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### University of Edinburgh, UK

Sept 2019 - present

PhD in Informatics (ICSA): Distributed systems, systems security, replication protocols

- · Sponsors: Microsoft Research, UK Rise, Advisor: Pramod Bhatotia
- · Design of robust distributed data management systems leveraging trusted hardware and byte-addressable storage.

#### University of Edinburgh, UK

Sept 2018 - Aug 2019

MSc in Computer Science: Software engineering, computer systems & high-performance computing

· Thesis: Rollback-Resilient Transaction Protocols using Trusted Counters (Best Performing Female MSc Student Award)

#### National Technical University of Athens (NTUA), Greece

Sept 2012 - Feb 2018

Diploma (5-year joint degree, BEng and MEng) in Electrical & Computer Engineering

· Thesis: Improving QoS in modern multi-core servers with Dynamic Cache Partitioning

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

#### Anchor: Secure Persistent Memory Architecture, SIGMOD'24

Dimitris Stravakakis, Dimitra Giantsidi, Maurice Bailleu, Philip Saendig, Shady Issa, Pramod Bhatotia.

## FlexLog: A Shared Log for Stateful Serverless Computing, ACM HPDC'23

Dimitra Giantsidi, Emmanouil Giortamis, Nathaniel Tornow, Florin Dinu, Pramod Bhatotia.

Treaty: Secure Distributed Transactions, IEEE/IFIP DSN'22 (Best paper nominee)

Dimitra Giantsidi, Maurice Bailleu, Natacha Crooks, Pramod Bhatotia.

### Avocado: A Secure In-Memory Distributed Storage System, USENIX ATC'21

Maurice Bailleu, Dimitra Giantsidi, Vasilis Gavrielatos, Le Quoc Do, Vijay Nagarajan, Pramod Bhatotia.

## DICER: Diligent Cache Partitioning for Efficient Workload Consolidation, ICPP'21

Konstantinos Nikas, Nikela Papadopoulou, Dimitra Giantsidi, Vasileios Karakostas, Georgios I Goumas, Nectarios Koziris.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages C/C++, Python, Bash, Golang, Java, Vitis HLS

Systems Programming RocksDB and folly libraries, TEEs (Intel SGX, OpenEnclave SDK, AMD-sev),

direct network I/O (DPDK, RDMA, Alveo SmartNICs), SPDK,

Intel RDT, LLVM, collectd, POSIX/Unix, OpenMP and MPI, gRPC

Virtualization KVM, Qemu/Libvirt, Docker, Kubernetes

Version Control

Git

**Distributed Programming** Hadoop MapReduce, Socket and RPC programming

## HONORS AND AWARDS

Research Grant, BaCaTec	2021
PhD scolarship, Microsoft Research	2019
Claire Jones Prize, Adelard Prize for Best Performing Female MSc Student at the University of Edinburgh	2019
Highest Honors award Top 0.1% in national qualification exams, GPA: 19.6/20	2012